Jerson L. Huerfano

Bogotá D.C, Colombia. $+57\ 312\ 5399279$

huerfano.jerson@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/jerson-huerfano-29827764

PROFILE

I am a Mechatronics engineer with 5 years of experience in Software Engineering. I am capable of handling multidisciplinary projects with exceptional proficiency in low and high-level system integration. I consider myself a skilled programmer, adhering to best practices to deliver high-quality solutions. Additionally, I am a flexible and self-organized individual familiar with agile methodologies and have mastered team leadership, guiding team members to overcome resistance to change. Furthermore, as an artificial intelligence enthusiast, I have completed Coursera's Deep Learning specialization.

EDUCATION

• B.E. Mechatronics Engineer, National University of Colombia, September 2017.

EDUCATION

COMPLEMENTARY. Introduction to artificial vision and hyperspectral images applied in agriculture, National University of Colombia, July 2017.

- CCNA Routing and switching, Cisco Network Academy.
- Specialized program: Deep learning, Coursera, license number EDNADUARR4D5
- Certified PEGA System architect, Pegasystems
- Professional Java SE 17 Developer, Oracle

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer Sonatype

January 2024 - today

- Develops, tests, and documents complex programs as per specifications.
- Reviews specifications with team.
- Support stage and production environments.

Key Skills: Java, PostgreSQL, JUnit, Mockito, AWS ECS, AWS S3, Terraform, Testcontainers, React, TDD, JIRA, Rally.

Senior Software Developer **Endava**

March 2021 - January 2024

- Designs, codes, tests, corrects and documents complex programs and program modifications from supplied specifications.
- Conducts reviews of supplied specifications, with others as appropriate.
- Provide support for standalone and distributed applications.

Key Skills: Java, Spring Boot, SQL Server, MongoDB, JUnit, Mockito, Spring MVC, C++, Visual C++ 2015, C#, OpenShift, AWS EKS, AWS S3, DynamoDB, Terraform, Kubernetes, Devcontainers, Copilot, OpenAPI, React, REST, TDD, JIRA, Rally.

- Analyzes technical specifications and suggest code optimizations.
- Interacts with customers on need basis and flag any requirements or issues raised by the customer to the team.
- Embraces organizational change positively by bringing about changes in own work practices.

Key Skills: PEGA, REST, Java, Low-Code, Rally, Agile

SS. Software Developer

January 2019 - May 2020

Conexia S.A.S. / IT solutions for healthcare industry

ONE-Colombia, Point of care solutions.

- Implements web-based projects using clean architecture, focused on frameworkindependent solutions.
- Ensures code quality and performance using static analysis and code coverage.
- Adopts Agile methodology and best code practices.
- Implements any country-specific regulations applicable to healthcare service.

Key Skills: Java, Spring Boot, Jakarta EE, Postgres, JUnit, Mockito, Spring MVC, Docker, Swagger, JSF, REST, TDD, DDD, JIRA.

Software Developer

November 2017 - November 2018

Parking International S.A.S, Bogota, CO.

Software Developer, Hardware and point of sale solutions

- Developed solutions and hardware integration for point-of-sale.
- Implemented cost-effective solution for automatic parking barriers.
- Designed Automatic number-plate recognition in compliance with country-specific regulations.

Key Skills: C++, gSOAP, pthreads, Boost, Java, Python, J2EE, SQL Server, MySQL, JUnit, Mockito, Copilot, Angular, REST, TDD, OpenLPR.

$Mechatronics\ Engineer$

October 2017 - November 2017

Lujociclas S.A.S, Bogota, CO.

- Implemented automation control for injection molding machine.
- Performed maintenance of electric and hydraulic components.

Key Skills: Java, C++, Swing, Arduino, SCADA, PLC, ModBus.

PROJECTS

- Public portfolio: https://github.com/hgl-team
- Personal portfolio: https://github.com/jlhuerfanor

PUBLICATIONS

 J. Huerfano, O. Ojeda, N. Alvarez, Telemetry system for trajectory estimation of vertical-ascent vehicles. at International Congress of Mechanical and Mechatronics Engineering CIMM 2015, Cartagena, 2015. • O. Ojeda, N. Alvarez, J. Huerfano, Workbench design for rocket engine testing and characterization. at International Congress of Mechanical and Mechatronics Engineering CIMM 2015, Cartagena, 2015.

SKILLLS

- Programming language: C/C++, Java (8-21), JavaScript, Typescript, C#, Python, Go.
- Frameworks: Spring framework (webmvc/reactive), J2/Jakarta EE, Asp.NET core, Angular, React, Inversify, Qt, Boost, Node.js, GraalVM
- Development platforms: Spring Boot, Node.js, GraalVM, Visual C++ 2015
- Development tools: Maven, Gradle, Apache Ant, CMake, Devcontainers, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse IDE, Git, JIRA, OpenAPI
- Testing tools: Gtest, Gmock, Spring Boot Test, JUnit (3-5), Mockito, Cucumber, Karate, Locust, Apache JMeter, Testcontainers
- DevOps tools: Docker, Podman, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform
- Databases: Postgres, SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle DB, DynamoDB
- Cloud service providers: AWS, OpenShift, GCP
- OS: Linux, Windows, Android.
- Others: SAFe, Scrum, TDD, DDD, Embedded systems.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Spanish: native Speaker.

English: C1 (IELTS Academic 2021).

German: B1.